A. James Delahoussaye collection of Atchafalaya River Basin recordings
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Guides to the Collections in the Archive of Folk Culture
A. James Delahoussaye collection of Atchafalaya River Basin recordings 1974-2010
AFC 2012/044
Delahoussaye, A. James, 1938-
785 items; .2 linear feet.
96 sound cassettes: analog.
635 photographs: digital, JPEG files, color, black and white.
49 transcripts (MS Word files)
4 sound files (WAV)
manuscripts: 1 folder.
Archive of Folk Culture, American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Collection of field recordings of interviews with Atchafalaya River Basin, Louisiana, residents about their lives, traditions, and folkways, recorded from 1974-2010, as well as approximately 645 digital images documenting the same traditions. Interviews were conducted by Alphe James (Jim) Delahoussaye. Digital images were created by his colleague, Darlene Soulé, of many of the same informants. Topics include fresh water fishing and shrimping, other animals and animal husbandry, cooking, medicine, weather, logging, community gatherings, religion and churches, boat building, courtship, marriage, and education. These residents of the Atchafalaya River Basin, many of whom were elderly at the time of the interviews, recall traditions and events experienced from the 1880s and through the 20th century. Photographs are digital copies of original family photographs dating from the 1920s to the present.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Bailey family.; Couvillier family.; Daigle family.; Delahoussaye, A. James, 1938-; Millet family; Sauce family.; Soulé, Darlene
Subjects
Bayous--Louisiana--Atchafalaya River Region.; Boatbuilding--Louisiana--Atchafalaya River Region.; Cajuns--Louisiana--Atchafalaya River Region--Folklore.; Cajuns--Louisiana--Atchafalaya River Region--Interviews.; Catholics--Louisiana--Atchafalaya River Region--Interviews.; Ecology--Louisiana--Atchafalaya River Region.; Environmental degradation--Louisiana--Atchafalaya River Region.; Field recordings--Louisiana.; Fishers--Louisiana--Atchafalaya River Region--Interviews.; Fishing--Louisiana--Atchafalaya River Region.; Food habits--Louisiana--Atchafalaya River Region.; Funeral rites and ceremonies--Louisiana--Atchafalaya River Region.; Ghost stories--Louisiana--Atchafalaya River Region.; Houseboats--Louisiana--Atchafalaya River Region.; Hunting stories--Louisiana--Atchafalaya River Region.; Levees--Louisiana--Atchafalaya River Region.; Relocation (Housing)--Louisiana--Atchafalaya River Region.; Shrimp culture--Louisiana--Atchafalaya River Region.; Traditional medicine--Louisiana--Atchafalaya River Region.
Places
Atchafalaya River Watershed (La.)--History.; Atchafalaya River Watershed (La.)--Social life and customs.; Saint Martin Parish (La.)--Genealogy.; Saint Martin Parish (La.)--History.; Saint Mary Parish (La.)--Genealogy.; Saint Mary Parish (La.)--History.
Form/Genre
Digital photographs.; Field recordings.; Oral histories.; Sound recordings.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into the following series: I. Manuscripts; II. Interviews and Events (arranged chronologically); and III. Photographs (arranged by file name).
Acquisition
A. James Delahoussaye; 2012.
Accruals
The bulk of the collection was received in 2012. Additional transcripts were acquired in 2014 and more may be acquired at a later date.
Access and Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Access may be restricted during processing. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Digital copies
Additional formats received with the collection (for tapes 1-83): 156 sound files, WAV: digital.
Biographical Note
A. James (Jim) Delahoussaye was born in New Iberia, Louisiana, in 1938. He is an environmental scientist, teacher, and commercial fisherman, who is working on the ethnology of the Atchafalaya houseboat communities and the analysis of animal bone from prehistoric Indian middens.
Scope and Content
Collection of field recordings of interviews with Atchafalaya River Basin, Louisiana, residents about their lives, traditions, and folkways, recorded from 1974-2010, as well as approximately 635 digital images documenting the same traditions. Interviews were conducted by Alphe James (Jim) Delahoussaye at the residences of the interviewees; at reunions, funerals, and other events; and also on boats and in cars. Digital images of family photographs, dating from the 1920s to the present, were created by his colleague, Darlene Soulé, of many of the same informants. Topics include fresh water fishing and shrimping, other animals and animal husbandry, cooking, medicine, weather, logging, community gatherings, religion and churches, boat building, courtship, marriage, and education. They also reflect on the building of levees in the area and environmental change and the histories of the Couvillier, Bailey, Sauce, Daigle, and Millet families. These residents of the Atchafalaya River Basin, many of whom were elderly at the time of the interviews, recall traditions and events experienced from the 1880s and through the 20th century.
Container List
- Series I: Manuscripts
  - Finding aid and summaries of interviews by A. James Delahoussaye (Box-folder 1/1)
- Series II: Interviews and Events
  Ninety-six recordings and 49 transcripts of 79 oral history interviews and events conducted by A. James Delahoussaye in the Atchafalaya River Basin, Louisiana, arranged chronologically.
  - Albert (Myon) Bailey, Agnes Bailey, Putt Couvillier, Edward Couvillier, and Lena Mae Couvillier oral history interview conducted by A. James Delahoussaye in St. Mary Parish, Louisiana., 1974
    Recorded at the residence of Albert (Myon) Bailey on Oxford Loop. Interviewees discuss Millet (Myette) Point, and the levee community.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio cassette (60 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR01
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (38 pages); afc2012044_sr001_transcript.doc
  - Albert (Myon) Bailey, Agnes Bailey, Putt Couvillier, Edward Couvillier, and Lena Mae Couvillier oral history interview conducted by A. James Delahoussaye in Millet (Myette) Point, St. Mary Parish, Louisiana, 1974
    Recorded at the levee at Millet (Myette) Point. Interviewees discuss Millet (Myette) Point, the levee community, and an air-cooled washing machine.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio cassette (67 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR02
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (40 pages); afc2012044_sr002_transcript.doc
  - Albert (Myon) Bailey, Agnes Bailey, Putt Couvillier, and Dorothy Couvillier oral history interview conducted by A. James Delahoussaye in Millet (Myette) Point, St. Mary Parish, Louisiana, 1974
    Recorded at the residence of Albert (Myon) Bailey on Oxford Loop and the residence of Albert (Putt) Couvillier. Interviewees discuss Millet (Myette) Point, the levee community, Blaise’s death story.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio cassette (61 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR03
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (31 pages); afc2012044_sr003_transcript.doc
  - Interview with Albert (Myon) Bailey, Agnes Bailey, Edward Couvillier, Lena Mae Couvillier, Kevin Couvillier, Carolyn Delahoussaye, and Dorothy Couvillier conducted by A. James Delahoussaye in Oxford, St. Mary Parish, Louisiana, January 26, 1989
    Recorded at the residence of Albert (Myon) and Agnes Bailey on Oxford Loop. Interviewees discuss illnesses, family, boats, fishing, and football.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio microcassette (58 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR04
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (36 pages); afc2012044_sr004_transcript.doc
  - Albert (Myon) Bailey and Agnes Bailey oral history interview conducted by A. James Delahoussaye in Oxford, St. Mary Parish, Louisiana, 1989
    Recorded at the residence of Albert (Myon) Bailey on Oxford Loop. Interviewees discuss a miscarriage and how they met.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio microcassette (75 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR05
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (46 pages); afc2012044_sr005_transcript.doc
  - Interview with Albert (Myon) Bailey and Agnes Bailey conducted by A. James Delahoussaye in Oxford, St. Mary Parish, Louisiana, 1989
    Recorded at the residence of Albert (Myon) Bailey on Oxford Loop. Interviewees discuss family history, food, funerals, cemeteries, and dating.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio microcassette (55 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR06
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (45 pages); afc2012044_sr006_transcript.doc
  - Comments by A. James Delahoussaye in Louisiana, November 20, 1992
    Recorded while riding in a vehicle. Delahoussaye's memories of the small commercial fishing industry in the Atchafalaya Basin and Albert (Myon) Bailey.
    - Sound recording, AFC 2012/044: SR07
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (17 pages); afc2012044_sr007_transcript.doc
  - Interview with Edward Couvillier and Lena Mae Couvillier conducted by A. James Delahoussaye in Oxford, St. Mary Parish, Louisiana, December 10, 1995
    Recorded at the residence of Edward Couvillier on Oxford Loop. Interviewees discuss the floods, houseboats, fishing and trapping, family, levee crossing in 1945, the Gondolfos, residents of Myon’s canal, location of the houseboat community, walking to school, and walking/rowing to visit the Burns.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio microcassette (63 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR08
    - Sound recording, 1 audio cassette (94 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR09
    - Sound recording, 1 audio cassette (94 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR10
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (59 pages); afc2012044_sr008_transcript.doc
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (67 pages); afc2012044_sr009_transcript.doc
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (64 pages); afc2012044_sr010_transcript.doc
  - Agnes Bailey, Edward Couvillier, Lena Mae Couvillier, and Dorothy Couvillier oral history interview conducted by A. James Delahoussaye in Oxford, St. Mary Parish, Louisiana, December 17, 1995
    Recorded at the residence of Edward Couvillier on Oxford Loop. Interviewees discuss home life, who crossed the levee, accidents, medicine, religion, school at Millet (Myette) Point, and genealogy.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio cassette (94 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR11
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (45 pages); afc2012044_sr011_transcript.doc
  - Joseph Sauce, Jr. and Florence Sauce oral history interview conducted by A. James Delahoussaye in Franklin, Louisiana, December 26, 1995
    Recorded at the residence of Joe Sauce, Jr., and his wife Florence Anslem Sauce. Interviewees discuss the Anslem family, houseboats, fishing technology, Lockwood Ash to air-cooleds to outboards, bugging, and seminary.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio cassette (93 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR12
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (38 pages); afc2012044_sr012_transcript.doc
  - Joseph Sauce, Jr., Florence Sauce, EJ Daigle, and Blue Daigle oral history interview conducted by A. James Delahoussaye in Franklin, Louisiana, December 26, 1995
    Recorded at residence of Joe Sauce, Jr., and his wife Florence Anslem Sauce. Interviewees discuss tools, putting out a line with hooks, outboards, and boats.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio cassette (93 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR13
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (41 pages); afc2012044_sr013_transcript.doc
  - EJ Daigle and Blue Daigle oral history interview conducted by A. James Delahoussaye in Franklin, Louisiana, December 26, 1995
    Recorded at the residence of EJ Daigle and his wife Blue. Interviewees discuss cribs, EJ's father's stroke, moves over the levee, tools, coastal shrimp, white eels, wire main line, Daigle property at 4 Mile, and baits.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio cassette (130 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR14
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (42 pages); afc2012044_sr014_transcript.doc
  - Edward Couvillier, Lena Mae Couvillier, Agnes Bailey, Joe Sauce, EJ Daigle, and Carolyn Delahoussaye oral history interview conducted by A. James Delahoussaye in Louisiana, December 28, 1995
    Recorded in a moving vehicle on a trip from Millet (Myette) Point to Napoleonville, Attakapas Landing, and Pierre Part, Louisiana. Interviewees discuss Bayou Chene, family, fishing, shrimping, taxes, dancing at the Rainbow Inn, and Pierre Part.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio microcassette (125 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR15
    - Sound recording, 1 audio microcassette (120 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR16
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (31 pages); afc2012044_sr015_transcript.doc
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (14 pages); afc2012044_sr016_transcript.doc
  - Cleo “Neg” Sauce, Edward Couvillier, and Lena Mae Couvillier oral history interview conducted by A. James Delahoussaye in Oxford, St. Mary Parish, Louisiana, January 2, 1996
    Recorded at Cleo “Neg” Sauce’s house at Oxford Loop. Interviewees discuss the Depression, daily life, nets and lines, fishing alone, medicine, injuries, music and playing, and philosophy of worldly goods.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio microcassette (102 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR17
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (50 pages); afc2012044_sr017_transcript.doc
  - Cleo “Neg” Sauce oral history interview conducted by A. James Delahoussaye in Oxford, St. Mary Parish, Louisiana, January 2, 1996
    Recorded at Cleo “Neg” Sauce’s house on Oxford Loop. Interviewee discusses moving over the levee and houseboat locations.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio cassette (65 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR18
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (30 pages); afc2012044_sr018_transcript.doc
  - Ida Daigle oral history interview conducted by James Delahoussaye in Oxford, St. Mary Parish, Louisiana, January 4, 1996
    Recorded at Ida Daigle’s house on Oxford Loop. Interviewee discusses the drowning of trees at Blaise’s Canal, the crab factory on Little Pigeon, courtship and her marriage to Jesse.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio cassette (94 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR19
    - Sound recording, 1 audio cassette (93 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR20
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (42 pages); afc2012044_sr019_transcript.doc
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (39 pages); afc2012044_sr020_transcript.doc
  - Russell Daigle oral history interview conducted by A. James Delahoussaye in Franklin, Louisiana, January 7, 1996
    Recorded at Russell Daigle’s house on Lee Charles St. Interviewee discusses family, the Anslem barge, his swamp philosophy, the use of nylon, sandbars on Goat Island, tools, weddings, and his campboat philosophy.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio cassette (94 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR21
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (49 pages); afc2012044_sr021_transcript.doc
  - Russell Daigle, Gale Daigle, and Matthew Daigle oral history interview conducted by A. James Delahoussaye in Franklin, Louisiana, January 7, 1996
    Recorded at Russell Daigle’s house on Lee Charles St. Interviewees discuss tools, baits, white eels, moving to Oxford, school, medicine, and Russell Daigle's philosophy on illness.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio cassette (76 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR22
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (40 pages); afc2012044_sr022_transcript.doc
  - Medric Martin, Edward Couvillier, and Agnes Bailey oral history interview conducted by A. James Delahoussaye in Oxford, St. Mary Parish, Louisiana, January 1996
    Recorded at Martin's general store on Irish Bend Road (LA 322) near location of old Oaklawn Sugar Mill and at Edward Couvillier’s house on Oxford Loop. Interviewees discuss Martin’s store, local people, mail, groceries, paid bills, Martin's relations with blacks, and the Millet (Myette) Point community.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio cassette (50 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR23
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (22 pages); afc2012044_sr023_transcript.doc
  - Ida Daigle, Roy "Bootsie" Millet, Gloria Ann Marcotte, Edward Couvillier, Lena Mae Couvillier, Alvin Marcotte, and Ophelia "Yank" Millet oral history interview conducted by A. James Delahoussaye in Oxford, St. Mary Parish, Louisiana, November 2, 1996 and January 2, 1997
    Recorded at Edward Couvillier’s house on Oxford Loop. Interviewees discuss the origin of the Millet family, plantation stores, smoking gar meat, Edward and Lena Mae Couvillier's courtship and marriage, tools, fishing techniques crosslines and bentlines, and carbide lamps.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio cassette (94 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR24
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (56 pages); afc2012044_sr024_transcript.doc
  - Edward Couvillier and Lena Mae Couvillier oral history interview conducted by A. James Delahoussaye in Oxford, St. Mary Parish, Louisiana, January 2, 1997
    Recorded at Edward Couvillier’s house on Oxford Loop. Interviewees discuss fishboat trips, the murder of Couvillier's uncle, chain dog use (logs), old tools, motors, move to get kids to school, Father Gobeil, baits, snakes, shrimp catching, white eels, “ansoirs,” first cars, burns, first whiskey roaches, fishboat, the peddler, and fishboat supplies.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio cassette (94 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR25
    - Sound recording, 1 audio microcassette (63 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR26
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (54 pages); afc2012044_sr025_transcript.doc
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (45 pages); afc2012044_sr026_transcript.doc
  - Neg Sauce oral history interview conducted by James Delahoussaye in Oxford, St. Mary Parish, Louisiana, January 1997
    Recorded at Neg Sauce’s house on Oxford Loop. Interviewee discusses tools, leaving the swamp, first use of nylon, and sandbars.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio cassette (64 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR27
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (31 pages); afc2012044_sr027_transcript.doc
  - Neg Sauce oral history interview conducted by James Delahoussaye in Oxford, St. Mary Parish, Louisiana, January 1997
    Recorded at Neg Sauce’s house on Oxford Loop. Interviewee discusses the death of Blaise Sauce, “ansoirs,” white eels, and his philosophy of the good life.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio cassette (47 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR28
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (24 pages); afc2012044_sr028_transcript.doc
  - Jerry Marcotte and Edward Couvillier oral history interview conducted by A. James Delahoussaye in Oxford, St. Mary Parish, Louisiana, August 23, 2003
    Recorded at Edward Couvillier’s house on Oxford Loop. Interviewees discuss levee building, barpits, houseboats, and seine fishing.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio cassette (49 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR29
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (21 pages); afc2012044_sr029_transcript.doc
  - Edward Couvillier, Lena Mae Couvillier, Margaret Couvillier Neal, and Evest Neal oral history interview conducted by A. James Delahoussaye in Lafayette, Louisiana, January 9, 2005
    Recorded in a hospital room. Interviewees discuss Hog Island school, livestock on cribs, making clothes, making quilts, making and maintaining moss mattresses, cornshucks mattresses, in-laws, midwives, snow at Millet (Myette) Point, the birth of Lena Mae's baby, washing floors and clothes, the garfish that took Lena Mae's ring, and being punished with kneeling.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio cassette (65 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR30
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (44 pages); afc2012044_sr030_transcript.doc
  - Bayou Chene Reunion in Morgan City, Louisiana, September 18, 2004
    Recorded at Lake End Park.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio microcassette (31 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR31
    - Sound recording, 1 audio microcassette (42 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR32
  - Dorothy Couvillier, Lena Mae Couvillier, Edward Couvillier, Danna Halpin, and Stanley Halpin conducted by A. James Delahoussaye and Danna Halpin in Franklin, Louisiana, February 2, 2005
    Recorded at Dorothy Couvillier’s house on Highway 87. Interviewees discuss breakfast foods, ways of cooking, preserving food in lard, views of early life, and medicines.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio cassette (60 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR33
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (26 pages); afc2012044_sr033_transcript.doc
  - Chris Daigle oral history interview conducted by James Delahoussaye in Louisiana, April 10, 2005
    Recorded at Chris Daigle's residence on Cayce St., Franklin, Louisiana.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio cassette (43 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR34
  - Edward Couvillier and Lena Mae Couvillier oral history interview conducted by A. James Delahoussaye, August 13, 2005
    Recorded at Edward Couvillier’s house on Oxford Loop. Interviewees discuss the river shrimp study, how river shrimp were harvested traditionally, other species of shrimp, maps, location of Blaise’s Canal, storms and rough water, and the openness of Grand Lake before sandbars.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio cassette (96 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR35
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (37 pages); afc2012044_sr035_transcript.doc
  - EJ Daigle and Blue Daigle oral history interview conducted by A. James Delahoussaye and Raymond T. Bauer in Franklin, Louisiana, August 13, 2005
    Recorded at the residence of EJ Daigle and his wife Blue on Milling Street. Interviewees discuss river shrimp, seasons, techniques of capture, other shrimp species, migration, sharks, jumping carp, and tarpon.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio cassette (90 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR36
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (26 pages); afc2012044_sr036_transcript.doc
  - Edward Couvillier, Lena Mae Couvillier, Ray Brassieur, and Jason Foster oral history interview conducted by A. James Delahoussaye in St. Mary Parish, Louisiana, September 17, 2004
    Recorded in a vehicle on the way to the Bayou Chene Reunion. Interviewees discuss The Pit in Morgan City and The Cutgrass Inn.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio microcassette (30 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR37
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (6 pages); afc2012044_sr037_transcript.doc
  - Edward Couvillier oral history interview conducted by A. James Delahoussaye in Raceland, Louisiana, March 8, 2006
    Recorded in a vehicle on the way to get boat plywood. Interviewees discuss tarring nets, cypress vs. tupelo, Lockwood cigarette lighter, moss gathering/industry, crawfish in old days, foggy times, duck hunting stories, a boat accident with Medric, ghost stories, logging, booming sinker logs, timber thieves, and Ben Law.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio cassette (102 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR38
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (39 pages); afc2012044_sr038_transcript.doc
  - Carl Carline oral history interview conducted by James Delahoussaye in Louisiana, April 5, 2006
    Recorded on board the COE Towboat MV Mississippi for the Mississippi River High Water Survey trip. Interviewee discusses his parents, mother was a midwife and healer, sawing firewood for family income, castrating pigs and cows, learning to fish, inventing a jiggerpole, father's work as a fishboat operator, education, food habits, houseboat life, the Burns murder, Joyce and Carl's courtship and married life, Joyce’s 16th birthday party, flying home on furlough, living in Texas and fishing in Louisiana, and building a pirogue.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio cassette (90 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR39
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (28 pages); afc2012044_sr039_transcript.doc
  - Edward Couvillier oral history interview conducted by A. James Delahoussaye in St. Mary Parish, Louisiana, April 15, 2006
    Recorded in a vehicle traveling from Morgan City to Franklin. Interviewees discuss cutting timber for the May Brothers, movies in Franklin, music at Charenton Beach, Son Burgess fighting at Charenton, and working in the mill and fishing.
    - Sound recording, 1 audio cassette 19 minutes); AFC 2012/044: SR40
    - Transcript, 1 MS Word file (9 pages); afc2012044_sr040_transcript.doc